CARTER GRANT

Full Stack Developer

Hong Kong

SUMMARY

Passionate Full Stack Developer with 6+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

01/2022 - Present

Scopic

Amsterdam, North Holland

- Successfully converted whole project from python 2 to 3.8.0
- Scripted unique test plans, test scripts and processes to remove previously known redundancy by 40% and ensured predictable outcomes
- Developed a desktop application to automate database testing process, improved efficiency by 65%
- Automated process to create usage graphs, saving \$500,000 / year & increasing accuracy

Frontend Developer

07/2021 - 11/2022

OneForma

West Loop, Chicago

- Moved the automation solution into a commercial software (\$60k/year)
- Designed and developed reusable software components which used in 3 different project with reducing development effort by 50%
- Re-engineered critical modules within a sprint to rely on a centralized library to optimize performance by 68%
- Rated with the best annual performance rating for all the years during my stint; given to top ~5% employees

Junior Web Developer

04/2019 - 06/2021

Storecove

Hilversum, North Holland

- Helped to increase the accuracy of the reporting systems by 4%
- Delivered configuration management tools to track server settings for performance testing which saved 25% of initial machine setup
- Developed monitor reports that are using in-memory cache, updating the data shown to the user every 1 second
- Optimized customer resources and reduce turnaround time by 20%
- Performed root cause analysis for more than 10 issues to identify bugs and rolled out fixes to production within 24 hours

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

04/2015 - 03/2019

The University of Hong Kong

Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong

Bachelor of Computer Science

04/2012 - 03/2015

Tai Kok Tsui Catholic Primary School

Tai Kok Tsui, Hong Kong

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Spearheaded a \$12M software project

From design to distribution as a senior software engineer in a 12-people team

30% improved query efficiency

By designing and fully revising the two largest MySQL databases

Coordinated a year-long release of a six-part platform project

With marketing, BA, QA, and sales department.

Chatbot implementation

Developed a chatbot which helped customer to reduce costs by 240% in their customer service department

SKILLS

Tools

HTML · CSS · PHP · Laravel · JavaScript ·

TypeScript · React · Next · Vue2 && Vue3 ·

 ${\sf TailwindCSS} \cdot {\sf Node.js} \cdot {\sf MySQL} \cdot \\$

 ${\sf MongoDB} \cdot {\sf PostgreSQL} \cdot {\sf Python} \cdot {\sf AI/ML} \cdot \\$

 $\mathsf{LLM} \cdot \mathsf{OpenAl} \cdot \mathsf{ChatGPT} \cdot \mathsf{LangChain}$

STRENGTHS

★ Application development expertise

Consistently improve applications, increasing user satisfaction

★ Innovative feature implementation

Effectively integrate new features enhancing performance

Client relationship management

Maintain excellent client relationships boosting revenue